Why do we cheat?
لماذا نخون؟
And why do happy people cheat?
ولماذا الأشخاص السعداء يخونون؟
And when we say "infidelity," what exactly do we mean?
وعندما نقول "خيانة" ماذا نعني بالضبط؟
Is it a hookup, a love story, paid sex, a chat room,
هي علاقة عابرة، قصة حب، جنس بأجر، غرف دردشة
a massage with a happy ending?
أم حصّة تدليك بنهاية سعيدة ؟
Why do we think that men cheat out of boredom and fear of intimacy,
لماذا نظن أن الرجال يخونون بسبب الملل والخوف من العلاقة الحميمية
but women cheat out of loneliness and hunger for intimacy?
بينما تخون النساء بسبب الوحدة والتعطش للعلاقة الحميمية
And is an affair always the end of a relationship?
وهذه مسألة دائما ما تنهي الزواج
For the past 10 years, I have traveled the globe
خلال العشرة سنوات الماضية، سافرت حول العالم
and worked extensively with hundreds of couples
وعملت على نطاق واسع مع مئات من الأزواج
who have been shattered by infidelity.
الذين دمّرتهم الخيانة الزوجية
There is one simple act of transgression
هناك فعل واحد بسيط للعدوان
that can rob a couple of their relationship,
الذي يمكن أن يَحْرم زوجين من ارتباطهما
their happiness and their very identity: an affair.
سعادتهما وهويتهما : علاقة -موازية للزواج-
And yet, this extremely common act is so poorly understood.
وحتى الآن، هذا التصرف الشائع بالكاد نفهمه
So this talk is for anyone who has ever loved.
إذن فهذه المحادثة لكل من وقع في الحب
Adultery has existed since marriage was invented,
الخيانة الزوجية وجدت منذ أن وجد الزواج
and so, too, the taboo against it.
وكذلك المجتمع يسكت عنه
In fact, infidelity has a tenacity that marriage can only envy,
في الواقع، الخيانة عنيدة حتى أن الزواج لا يستطيع إلا أن يغار منها
so much so, that this is the only commandment
لدرجة، أن هذه هي الوصية الوحيدة
that is repeated twice in the Bible:
التي تتكرر مرتين في الكتاب المقدس
once for doing it, and once just for thinking about it.
مرة للقيام بها، وأخرى لمجرد التفكير فيها
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So how do we reconcile what is universally forbidden,
إذن كيف نُوفِّق بين ما هو ممنوع عالميا
yet universally practiced?
وما هو ممارس عالميا
Now, throughout history, men practically had a license to cheat
الآن ، على مر التاريخ ، الرجال لديهم في الواقع ترخيص للخيانة
with little consequence,
مع عواقب بسيطة
and supported by a host of biological and evolutionary theories
وبدعم من مجموع النظريات البيولوجية والتطورية
that justified their need to roam,
التي تبرر حاجتهم للتجوال
so the double standard is as old as adultery itself.
لهذا فالمعايير المزدوجة قديمة قِدمَ الخيانة نفسها
But who knows what's really going on under the sheets there, right?
لكن من يدري ماذا يحدث حقّاً تحت الأغطية، أليس كذلك؟
Because when it comes to sex,
لأنه أثناء العملية الجنسية
the pressure for men is to boast and to exaggerate,
الضغط على الرجال للتباهي والمبالغة
but the pressure for women is to hide, minimize and deny,
لكن الضغط على النساء لإخفاء وتهوين وإنكار،
which isn't surprising when you consider that there are still nine countries
وليس من المستغرب معرفة أنه لا تزال هناك تسع دول
where women can be killed for straying.
يمكن أن تقتل فيها المرأة بسبب الإنحراف.
Now, monogamy used to be one person for life.
الآن، الزواج الأحادي يربطنا بشخص كل الحياة
Today, monogamy is one person at a time.
اليوم الزواج الأحادي يربطنا بشخص كل مرة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
I mean, many of you probably have said,
أعني، قد قالها الكثير منكم
"I am monogamous in all my relationships."
"أنا لدي شريك واحد في كل علاقاتي."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
We used to marry,
سابقا كنا نتزوج
and had sex for the first time.
ونمارس الجنس أول مرة
But now we marry,
لكن الآن نتزوج
and we stop having sex with others.
فنتوقف عن ممارسة الجنس من الآخرين
The fact is that monogamy had nothing to do with love.
الواقع أن الزواج الآحادي لا علاقة له بالحب
Men relied on women's fidelity
يعتمد الرجال على إخلاص النساء
in order to know whose children these are,
ليعرفوا أن الأطفال أبناؤهم
and who gets the cows when I die.
ومن سيرث البقرة عندما أموت
Now, everyone wants to know
الآن ، كل شخص يريد أن يعرف
what percentage of people cheat.
كم نسبة الأشخاص الذين يخونون
I've been asked that question since I arrived at this conference.
لقد طرح عليّ هذا السؤال منذ وصولي هذا المؤتمر
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
It applies to you.
هذا ينطبق عليكم
But the definition of infidelity keeps on expanding:
لكن تعريف الخيانة يبقى فضفاضا
sexting, watching porn, staying secretly active on dating apps.
جنس عبر الرسائل، ومشاهدة الاباحية، والتواعد سرا عن طريق التطبيقات.
So because there is no universally agreed-upon definition
لهذا لا يوجد تعريف متوافق عليه عالميا
of what even constitutes an infidelity,
أو حتى ما يشكل الخيانة الزوجية
estimates vary widely, from 26 percent to 75 percent.
التقديرات تختلف كثيرا ما بين 26 و 75 بالمئة
But on top of it, we are walking contradictions.
بل أكثر من هذا، إننا نعيش التناقض
So 95 percent of us will say that it is terribly wrong
وبالتالي %95 بالمئة منا سيقولون أن هذا خطأ فادح
for our partner to lie about having an affair,
في حق شريكنا أن نكذب عليه بشأن وجود علاقة غرامية
but just about the same amount of us will say
لكن العدد نفسه منّا سيقول
that that's exactly what we would do if we were having one.
أن هذا بالضبط ما سيفعلونه إذا كانت لديهم هذه العلاقة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Now, I like this definition of an affair --
الآن، يعحبني هذا التعريف للعلاقة -الموازية للزواج-
it brings together the three key elements:
إنه يجمع بين العناصر الرئيسية الثلاثة
a secretive relationship, which is the core structure of an affair;
علاقة سرية، وهو الهيكل الأساسي للعلاقة غير الشرعية
an emotional connection to one degree or another;
اتصال عاطفي إلى درجة ما
and a sexual alchemy.
وخيمياء جنسي
And alchemy is the key word here,
والخيمياء هي الكلمة الأساسية هنا،
because the erotic frisson is such that the kiss that you only imagine giving,
لأن الرعشة الشهوانية كتلك القبلة التي تتخيلها فقط
can be as powerful and as enchanting
قد تكون بقوة السحر
as hours of actual lovemaking.
مثل ساعات ممارسة الحب
As Marcel Proust said,
كما قال مارسيل بروست
it's our imagination that is responsible for love, not the other person.
إن مخيلتنا هي المسؤولة عن الحب وليس الطرف الأخر
So it's never been easier to cheat,
لذلك فإنه لم يكن من السهل الخيانة،
and it's never been more difficult to keep a secret.
ولا شيء أصعب من الحفاظ على السرية.
And never has infidelity exacted such a psychological toll.
ولم يتم أبداً اعتبار الخيانة كعبءٍ نفسي
When marriage was an economic enterprise,
عندما كان الزواج مؤسسة اقتصادية
infidelity threatened our economic security.
الخيانة تهدد أمننا الاقتصادي
But now that marriage is a romantic arrangement,
لكن الآن الزواج هو ترتيب رومانسي
infidelity threatens our emotional security.
الخيانة تهدد أمننا العاطفي
Ironically, we used to turn to adultery --
ومن المفارقات، أننا نتوجّه إلى الخيانة الزوجية
that was the space where we sought pure love.
ذلك الفضاء الذي نسعى فيه إلى الحب النقي
But now that we seek love in marriage,
لكن الآن عندما نبحث عن الحب في الزواج
adultery destroys it.
الخيانة الزوجية تدمّره
Now, there are three ways that I think infidelity hurts differently today.
الآن، هناك ثلاث طرق أعتقد أن الخيانة تضرّ بها اليوم
We have a romantic ideal in which we turn to one person
لدينا مثالية رومانسية نتوجه فيها إلى شخص واحد
to fulfill an endless list of needs:
لتحقيق تلك اللائحة اللانهائية من الرغبات
to be my greatest lover, my best friend,
لتكون عشيقي الأكبر وصديقي الأفضل
the best parent, my trusted confidant,
والوالد الأفضل ، وصديقي الحميم
my emotional companion, my intellectual equal.
ورفيقي العاطفي وندّي الذكي
And I am it: I'm chosen, I'm unique,
وهذا أنا ، أنا مختار أنا فريد من نوعه
I'm indispensable, I'm irreplaceable,
أنا من لا غنى عنه أنا من لا بديل له
I'm the one.
لا مثيل لي
And infidelity tells me I'm not.
والخيانة تقول لي عكس ذلك
It is the ultimate betrayal.
إنها الخيانة العظمى
Infidelity shatters the grand ambition of love.
الخيانة تدمر الطموح الكبير للحب
But if throughout history, infidelity has always been painful,
وعبر التاريخ الخيانة كانت دائما مؤلمة
today it is often traumatic,
واليوم غالبا ما تكون صادمة
because it threatens our sense of self.
لأنها تهدد أحساسنا بذواتنا
So my patient Fernando, he's plagued.
أيضا مريضي فرناندو، إنه يعاني
He goes on: "I thought I knew my life.
يقول: "كنت أعتقد أنني أعرف حياتي"
I thought I knew who you were, who we were as a couple, who I was.
كنت أعتقد أنني عرفت من أنت ، من نحن كزوجين ، من كُنتُ
Now, I question everything."
الآن أتساءل عن كل شيء
Infidelity -- a violation of trust, a crisis of identity.
الخيانة الزوجية -- اغتصاب للحقيقة أزمة هوية
"Can I ever trust you again?" he asks.
"هل يمكنني الوثوق بك مرة أخرى" يتساءل
"Can I ever trust anyone again?"
"هل يمكنني الوثوق بأي شخص آخر مجددا "
And this is also what my patient Heather is telling me,
وهذا ما قالته لي أيضا مريضتي -هيذر-
when she's talking to me about her story with Nick.
عندما قالت لي قصّتها مع -نيك-
Married, two kids.
متزوجان، لديهما طفلان
Nick just left on a business trip,
نيك غادر لتوه في رحلة عمل،
and Heather is playing on his iPad with the boys,
وهيذر تلعب على الآيبّاد مع الأولاد،
when she sees a message appear on the screen:
وعندها رأت رسالة تظهر على الشاشة
"Can't wait to see you."
"لا أستطيع الانتظار لرؤيتك"
Strange, she thinks, we just saw each other.
غريب، تفكر، لقد رأينا بعضنا للتو
And then another message:
ثم رسالة أخرى
"Can't wait to hold you in my arms."
" لا أستطيع الانتظار لأضمّك في حضني"
And Heather realizes
وتدرك هيذر
these are not for her.
أن هذه الرسائل ليست لها
She also tells me that her father had affairs,
وأخبرتني أيضا أن والدها كانت له علاقة - موازية للزواج-
but her mother, she found one little receipt in the pocket,
لكن والدتها وجدت أيصالا صغيرا في الجيب
and a little bit of lipstick on the collar.
وآثارا لأحمر الشفاه على ياقات القميص
Heather, she goes digging,
هيذر ، وبدأت التحرّي
and she finds hundreds of messages,
ووجدَتْ مئات من الرسائل
and photos exchanged and desires expressed.
وصور متبادلة ورسائل غرامية
The vivid details of Nick's two-year affair
وتفاصيل حية لعلاقة نيك الغرامية ذات السنتين
unfold in front of her in real time,
تتكشف أمام عينيها في الوقت الحقيقي
And it made me think:
ومما جعلني أعتقد
Affairs in the digital age are death by a thousand cuts.
أن العلاقات الغرامية السرية في العصر الرقمي هي موت بألف قطعة
But then we have another paradox that we're dealing with these days.
ولكن بعد ذلك لدينا مفارقة أخرى أن نتعامل مع هذه الأيام
Because of this romantic ideal,
بسبب هذه الرومانسية المثالية
we are relying on our partner's fidelity with a unique fervor.
نعتمد على إخلاص الشريك مع حماسة فريدة من نوعها
But we also have never been more inclined to stray,
لكن أيضا لم نكن أبدا أكثر ميلا إلى الطيش
and not because we have new desires today,
ليس لأنه لدينا رغبات جديدة اليوم
but because we live in an era
ولكن لأننا نعيش في عصر
where we feel that we are entitled to pursue our desires,
حيث نشعر بأنه يحق لنا اتباع رغباتنا
because this is the culture where I deserve to be happy.
لأن هذه هي الثقافة التي تجعلني أستحق أن أكون سعيدا
And if we used to divorce because we were unhappy,
وإذا كنا نلجأ للطلاق لأننا لم نكن سعداء
today we divorce because we could be happier.
اليوم نلجأ للطلاق لأننا قد نكون أكثر سعادة
And if divorce carried all the shame,
واذا كان الطلاق يحمل كل العار،
today, choosing to stay when you can leave
اليوم نختار البقاء عندما يمكننا المغادرة
is the new shame.
هذا هو العار الجديد
So Heather, she can't talk to her friends
ولهذا هيذر، لا تستطيع التحدث مع صديقاتها
because she's afraid that they will judge her for still loving Nick,
لأنها تخشى أنهن سيحكمن عليها بأنها لا تزال تحب نيك
and everywhere she turns, she gets the same advice:
وحيثما ذهبت تحصل على نفس النصيحة
Leave him. Throw the dog on the curb.
اتركيه اِرمي الكلب على الرصيف
And if the situation were reversed, Nick would be in the same situation.
وإذا تم عكس هذا الوضع، سوف نيك يكون في نفس الحالة
Staying is the new shame.
البقاء هو العار الجديد
So if we can divorce,
حتى إذا كنا نستطيع الطلاق
why do we still have affairs?
لماذا نحتفظ بتلك العلاقات؟
Now, the typical assumption is that if someone cheats,
الآن، فإن الافتراض النموذجي إذا ما خان شخص ما
either there's something wrong in your relationship or wrong with you.
إما أن هناك شيء خاطئ في علاقتك أو الخطأ فيك
But millions of people can't all be pathological.
ولكن الملايين من الناس لا يمكن أن يكونوا كلهم مرضى
The logic goes like this: If you have everything you need at home,
هكذا هو المنطق: إذا كان لديك كل ما تحتاجه في المنزل،
then there is no need to go looking elsewhere,
ثم ليست هناك حاجة لتذهب للبحث في مكان آخر
assuming that there is such a thing as a perfect marriage
على افتراض أن هناك شيء اسمه الزواج المثالي
that will inoculate us against wanderlust.
الذي قد يُطعِّمنا ضد شهوة حب التجوال.
But what if passion has a finite shelf life?
ولكن ماذا إذا كان للشغف صلاحية محدودة؟
What if there are things that even a good relationship
ماذا إذا كانت هناك أشياء لا تستطيع حتى علاقة جيدة
can never provide?
أن تقدِّمها؟
If even happy people cheat,
حتى الأشخاص السعداء يخونون
what is it about?
ما هذا؟
The vast majority of people that I actually work with
الغالبية العظمى من الناس الذين أعمل معهم حاليا
are not at all chronic philanderers.
ليسوا كلهم مدمنين على التغزل
They are often people who are deeply monogamous in their beliefs,
أنهم غالبا ما يكونون عميقي الاعتقاد بالوفاء للزواج الأحادي
and at least for their partner.
وعلى الأقل لشريكهم
But they find themselves in a conflict
لكنها يجدون أنفسهم في صراع
between their values and their behavior.
بين قيمهم وسلوكهم
They often are people who have actually been faithful for decades,
هم غالبا أشخاص كانوا أوفياء على مدى عقود
but one day they cross a line
لكن يوماً ما تجاوزوا خطًّا
that they never thought they would cross,
لم يتوقعوا أبدا تجاوزه
and at the risk of losing everything.
وأمام خطر فقدان كل شيء
But for a glimmer of what?
لكن لبصيص لأي شيء؟
Affairs are an act of betrayal,
العلاقات الغير شرعية هي عمل من أعمال الخيانة
and they are also an expression of longing and loss.
وهي أيضا تعبير عن الشوق والضياع
At the heart of an affair, you will often find
في قلب علاقة، سوف تجد أحيانا
a longing and a yearning for an emotional connection,
شوق وتوق للاتصال العاطفي
for novelty, for freedom, for autonomy, for sexual intensity,
للبحث عن الجديد، من أجل الحرية، من أجل الاستقلال، للفورة الجنسية
a wish to recapture lost parts of ourselves
والرغبة في استعادة الأجزاء المفقودة من أنفسنا
or an attempt to bring back vitality in the face of loss and tragedy.
أو محاولة لاعادة الحيوية في مواجهة الخسارة والمأساة
I'm thinking about another patient of mine, Priya,
أنا أفكر في مريضتي الأخرى، بريا
who is blissfully married,
التي تزوجت في سعادة
loves her husband,
تحب زوجها
and would never want to hurt the man.
ولم تكن تريد أن تؤذي هذا الرجل
But she also tells me
لكنها أخبرتني أيضاً
that she's always done what was expected of her:
أنها كانت دوما تؤدّي ما كان متوقّعا منها
good girl, good wife, good mother,
فتاة صالحة، زوجة صالحة، أم صالحة
taking care of her immigrant parents.
قامت برعاية والديها المهاجرين
Priya, she fell for the arborist who removed the tree from her yard
بريا، لقد وقعت في حب البستاني الذي أزال شجرة من حديقتها
after Hurricane Sandy.
بعد إعصار ساندي
And with his truck and his tattoos, he's quite the opposite of her.
وبشاحنته ووشومه قد يكون عكسها تماما
But at 47, Priya's affair is about the adolescence that she never had.
ولكن في سنّ 47، علاقة بريا هذه تمثل المراهقة التي لم تعشها من قبل
And her story highlights for me that when we seek the gaze of another,
وقصتها أبرزت لي أنه عندما نبحث في نظرات الآخر
it isn't always our partner that we are turning away from,
وهو ليس دائما شريكنا الذي ابتعدنا عنه
but the person that we have ourselves become.
ولكن الشخص الذي وجدنا فيه أنفسنا
And it isn't so much that we're looking for another person,
فليس بحثنا عن شخص آخر
as much as we are looking for another self.
إلا بحثنا عن نفسنا
Now, all over the world,
الآن، حول العالم بأسره
there is one word that people who have affairs always tell me.
هناك كلمة واحدة يخبرني بها دائما الأشخاص الذين لهم هذه العلاقات
They feel alive.
إنهم يشعرون بالحياة
And they often will tell me stories of recent losses --
وغالبا ما يحكون لي قصصا عن خسائرهم الأخيرة
of a parent who died,
كوفاة أحد الوالدين
and a friend that went too soon,
أو صديق غادر بسرعة
and bad news at the doctor.
أو خبر سيء عند الطبيب
Death and mortality often live in the shadow of an affair,
الموت والوفاة غالبا ما يعيش في ظل العلاقات الموازية للزواج
because they raise these questions.
لأنها تثير هذه الأسئلة
Is this it? Is there more?
هل هذا هو؟ هناك أكثر من ذلك؟
Am I going on for another 25 years like this?
هل سأمضي 25 سنة أخرى على هذا النحو
Will I ever feel that thing again?
هل سيراودني هذا الإحساس مرة أخرى؟
And it has led me to think that perhaps these questions
وهذا ما قادني للتفكير أنه ربما هذه الأسئلة
are the ones that propel people to cross the line,
هي التي تدفع الناس لتجاوز الخط
and that some affairs are an attempt to beat back deadness,
ان بعض هذه العلاقات هي محاولة لمواجهة ضعف التأثير
in an antidote to death.
في ترياق للموت
And contrary to what you may think,
و عكس ما قد تعتقده
affairs are way less about sex, and a lot more about desire:
هذه العلاقات معبرٌ للقليل من للجنس ولكمٍّ هائل من للرغبات
desire for attention, desire to feel special,
الرغبة في الاهتمام الرغبة في الإحساس بالتميز
desire to feel important.
الرغبة في الإحساس بالأهمية
And the very structure of an affair,
والهيكل الأساسي لعلاقة
the fact that you can never have your lover,
حقيقة أنك لن تقدر على ترك
keeps you wanting.
عاشقك ينتظر
That in itself is a desire machine,
إنها نفسها آلية للرغبات
because the incompleteness, the ambiguity,
بسبب النقص والغموض
keeps you wanting that which you can't have.
تجعلك ترغب في ما لا تملك
Now some of you probably think
الآن بعضكم قد يفكر
that affairs don't happen in open relationships,
أن العلاقات الموازية للزواج لا تحدُث في الارتباط المنفتح
but they do.
لكنها تحدُث
First of all, the conversation about monogamy is not the same
قبل أي شيء، الحديث عن الزواج الأحادي ليس هو نفس
as the conversation about infidelity.
الحديث عن الخيانة الزوجية
But the fact is that it seems that even when we have
ولكن الحقيقة هي أنه يبدو أنه حتى عندما يكون لدينا
the freedom to have other sexual partners,
الحرية في الحصول على شركاء جنسيين آخرين
we still seem to be lured by the power of the forbidden,
نبقى على ما يبدو تحت إغراء سلطة المحرَّمات
that if we do that which we are not supposed to do,
عندما نفعل ما لا يفترض بنا فعله
then we feel like we are really doing what we want to.
ثم نحس كأننا نفعل ما نريده حقّاً
And I've also told quite a few of my patients
وقد أخبرت عدداً غير قليل من مرضاي
that if they could bring into their relationships
إذا كان بإمكانهم أن يجلبوا لزواجهم
one tenth of the boldness, the imagination and the verve
عُشُر الجُرأة والخيال والحيوية
that they put into their affairs,
الذي يمنحونه لعلاقاتهم الموازية
they probably would never need to see me.
ربما لن يكونوا في حاجة لرؤيتي
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So how do we heal from an affair?
كيف لنا إذن أن نشفى من هذه العلاقات ؟
Desire runs deep.
رغبة تتوغّل بعمق
Betrayal runs deep.
خيانة تتوغّل بعمق
But it can be healed.
لكن يمكن أن تشفى
And some affairs are death knells
وبعض هذه العلاقات تقرع نواقيس الموت
for relationships that were already dying on the vine.
لارتباط زواج قد أثبت فشله
But others will jolt us into new possibilities.
لكن البعض سوف يردّنا بقوة نحو حقائق جديدة
The fact is, the majority of couples
حقيقة أن غالبية الأزواج
who have experienced affairs stay together.
الذين عاشوا هذه العلاقات لم ينفصلوا
But some of them will merely survive,
لكن البعض منهم سيعيشون فقط
and others will actually be able to turn a crisis into an opportunity.
والآخرون سيكون بإمكانهم تحويل الأزمة إلى فرصة
They'll be able to turn this into a generative experience.
سيكون بإمكانهم تحويلها إلى تجربة بنّاءة
And I'm actually thinking even more so for the deceived partner,
وأنا حاليا أفكر حتى أكثر من ذلك بالنسبة للشريك المخدوع
who will often say,
من الذي سيقول أحيانا
"You think I didn't want more?
"هل تعتقدين أنني لم أرغب بالمزيد
But I'm not the one who did it."
لكني لست من فعلها"
But now that the affair is exposed,
لكن بعد أن انكشفت العلاقة السرية
they, too, get to claim more,
سيكشفان المزيد
and they no longer have to uphold the status quo
وأنّهما ليسا ملزمين بالاستمرار على الوضع الراهن
that may not have been working for them that well, either.
وهذا لا يعني أننا لا نعمل من أجلهم بشكل جيد أيضا
I've noticed that a lot of couples,
لاحظت أن الكثير من الأزواج
in the immediate aftermath of an affair,
في أعقاب علاقة غرامية موازية للزواج،
because of this new disorder that may actually lead to a new order,
وبسبب هذا الاضطراب الجديد الذي قد يقود نحو نظام جديد
will have depths of conversations with honesty and openness
ستكون محادثاتهم عميقة كلّها أمانة وانفتاح
that they haven't had in decades.
لم تكن فيهم منذ عقود
And, partners who were sexually indifferent
والشركاء الذين كانوا غير مبالين بالجنس
find themselves suddenly so lustfully voracious,
سيجدون أنفسهم فجأة شهوانيين بشراهة
they don't know where it's coming from.
لا يعرفون كيف حصل هذا
Something about the fear of loss will rekindle desire,
شيء من الخوف من الضياع سيقوم بإحياء الرغبة
and make way for an entirely new kind of truth.
وإفساح الطريق كليا لنوع جديد من الحقيقة
So when an affair is exposed,
إذن، عندما تنكشف العلاقة
what are some of the specific things that couples can do?
ما هي بعض الأشياء المحددة يمكن أن يفعلها الأزواج؟
We know from trauma that healing begins
ونعلم من الصدمة أن التعافي بدأ
when the perpetrator acknowledges their wrongdoing.
عندما يعترف الجاني بذنبه
So for the partner who had the affair,
بالنسبة للجاني الذي قام بهذه العلاقة
for Nick,
بالنسبة ل"نيك"
one thing is to end the affair,
شيء هو إنهاء هذه العلاقة غير الشرعية
but the other is the essential, important act of expressing
ولكن بالنسبة للشريك الآخر المهم هو طريقة التعبير
guilt and remorse for hurting his wife.
عن الشعور بالذنب والندم على ايذاء زوجته
But the truth is
لكن الحقيقة هي
that I have noticed that quite a lot of people who have affairs
أن عددا غير قليل من الأشخاص المتورطين في علاقات
may feel terribly guilty for hurting their partner,
قد يحسون بشعور رهيب بالذنب لإيذاء شريكهم
but they don't feel guilty for the experience of the affair itself.
ولكن لا يشعرون بالذنب بسبب تجربة العلاقة نفسها
And that distinction is important.
وهذا التمييز مهم
And Nick, he needs to hold vigil for the relationship.
نيك، يجب عليه الحرص على زواجه
He needs to become, for a while, the protector of the boundaries.
يجب عليه، لفترة، أن يحمي حدوده
It's his responsibility to bring it up,
أنها مسؤوليته أن يجلبها
because if he thinks about it,
لأنه إذا كان يفكر فيها
he can relieve Heather from the obsession,
يمكنه التخفيف من هواجس هيذر
and from having to make sure that the affair isn't forgotten,
ومن محاولاتها للتحقق من انتهاء علاقته ونسيانه لها
and that in itself begins to restore trust.
ثم تبدأ من داخلها باستعادة الثقة
But for Heather,
لكن هيذر
or deceived partners,
أو الشريك المخدوع
it is essential to do things that bring back a sense of self-worth,
من الضروري القيام بأمور تساعد على استرجاع الثقة بالنفس
to surround oneself with love and with friends and activities
وأن تحيط نفسها بالحب الأصدقاء والأنشطة
that give back joy and meaning and identity.
التي تعيد السعادة والمعنى و الهوية
But even more important,
ولكن الأهم
is to curb the curiosity to mine for the sordid details --
هو الحد من الفضول نحو الألغام والتفاصيل البائسة
Where were you? Where did you do it?
أين كنت؟ أين فعلتها ؟
How often? Is she better than me in bed? --
كم مرة؟ هل هي أفضل مني فى السرير؟
questions that only inflict more pain,
أسئلة لا تنتج إلا المزيد من الألم
and keep you awake at night.
وتبقيك مستيقظا طول الليل
And instead, switch to what I call the investigative questions,
وبدلا من ذلك، التحول إلى ما أسميه أسئلة التحقيق
the ones that mine the meaning and the motives --
تلك التي تستهدف المعنى والدوافع
What did this affair mean for you?
ماذا تعني لك هذه العلاقة؟
What were you able to express or experience there
ماذا كنت قادرا على التعبير عنه أو تجربته
that you could no longer do with me?
ولم تكن قادرا على الحصول عليه معي؟
What was it like for you when you came home?
كيف كنت تراني عندما عند عودتك للبيت؟
What is it about us that you value?
ماذا كنّا نعني لك؟
Are you pleased this is over?
أنت سعيد بنهاية تلك العلاقة؟
Every affair will redefine a relationship,
كل علاقة غير مشروعة ستعيد تعريف العلاقة الزوجية
and every couple will determine
وكل زوجين سيحددان
what the legacy of the affair will be.
كيف ستكون تبعات تلك العلاقة
But affairs are here to stay, and they're not going away.
لكن العلاقات -الموازية للزواج- وجدت لتبقى ولن تذهب بعيداً
And the dilemmas of love and desire,
ومعضلات الحب والرغبة
they don't yield just simple answers of black and white and good and bad,
أنها لا تسفر عن إجابات بسيطة فقط عن الأبيض والأسود والخير والشر
and victim and perpetrator.
والضحية والجاني
Betrayal in a relationship comes in many forms.
الخيانة داخل الزواج تظهر في أشكال عديدة
There are many ways that we betray our partner:
هناك حالات كثيرة نخون فيها شريكنا
with contempt, with neglect,
بالازدراء، بالإهمال
with indifference, with violence.
باللامبالاة ، بالعنف
Sexual betrayal is only one way to hurt a partner.
الخيانة الجنسية ليست إلا حالة واحدة لإيذاء الشريك
In other words, the victim of an affair
وبكلمات أخرى، ضحية العلاقة
is not always the victim of the marriage.
ليس دائما هو ضحية الزواج
Now, you've listened to me,
الآن، استمعت إليّ
and I know what you're thinking:
وأعلم ما تفكر فيه
She has a French accent, she must be pro-affair.
لديها لَـكْـنةٌ فرنسية لا بد أنها مؤيدة العلاقات الموازية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So, you're wrong.
إذن أنت مخطئ
I am not French.
أنا لست فرنسية
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
And I'm not pro-affair.
وأنا لست مؤيدة علاقات
But because I think that good can come out of an affair,
لأنني أعتقد أن الأفضل يمكن أن يأتي بعيدا عن العلاقة
I have often been asked this very strange question:
سُئلت غالبا هذا السؤال الغريب:
Would I ever recommend it?
هل توصين بها ؟
Now, I would no more recommend you have an affair
الآن، لن أوصيك بالقيام بعلاقة
than I would recommend you have cancer,
بقدر ما سأوصيك بأن تصاب بالسرطان
and yet we know that people who have been ill
وحتى الآن نحن نعلم أن الأشخاص أصيبوا بمرض
often talk about how their illness has yielded them a new perspective.
غالبا ما يحكون كيف أن مرضهم أكسبهم منظورا جديدا.
The main question that I've been asked since I arrived at this conference
السؤال الرئيسي الذي طرح علي منذ وصولي المؤتمر
when I said I would talk about infidelity is, for or against?
عندما قلت أنني سأتكلم عن الخيانة الزوجية هو: مع أم ضدّ؟
I said, "Yes."
قلت : نعم
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I look at affairs from a dual perspective:
أنا أنظر إلى العلاقات من منظور مزدوج
hurt and betrayal on one side,
أذى وخيانة من جهة
growth and self-discovery on the other --
نموّ واكتشاف للنفس في الجهة الأخرى
what it did to you, and what it meant for me.
ماذا فعلت بكم وماذا كانت تعني لي
And so when a couple comes to me in the aftermath of an affair
وهكذا عندما يأتي عندي زوجان عقب علاقة لأحدهما
that has been revealed,
تم انكشافهما
I will often tell them this:
سأخبرهما دوما بهذا:
Today in the West,
اليوم في الغرب
most of us are going to have two or three relationships
الكثير منا ستكون لهم علاقتان أو ثلاث
or marriages,
أو زواج
and some of us are going to do it with the same person.
وبعضنا سيقومون بها مع الشخص نفسه
Your first marriage is over.
زواجك الأول انتهى
Would you like to create a second one together?
هل تريد أن نبدأ زواجا آخر معاً؟
Thank you.
شكراً لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)